Based on the extraordinary true story
The Blind Side is a drama film directed by John Lee Hancock.
The story of Michael Oher, a homeless and traumatized boy who became an All American football
player and first round NFL draft pick with the help of a caring woman and her family.
Leigh Anne Tuohy, played by Sandra Bullock.
Sean Tuohy, played by Tim McGraw.
Michael Oher, played by Quinton Aaron.
S.J. Tuohy, played by Jae Head.
Collins Tuohy, played by Lily Collins.
Coach Cotton, played by Ray McKinnon.
The Blind Side is a 2009 American biographical sports drama
film written and directed by John Lee Hancock.
Based on the 2006 book of the same name by Michael Lewis, the film tells the story of Michael Oher, a football offensive lineman who
overcame an impoverished upbringing to play in the National Football League (NFL) with the help of Leigh Anne and Sean Tuohy.
It stars Sandra Bullock as Leigh Anne, Tim McGraw
as Sean, and Quinton Aaron as Oher.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $309
million on a $29 million budget.
Despite mixed reviews from critics, Bullock's performance was universally praised, leading to her winning the Academy Award for Best Actress, the Golden Globe
Award for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama, and the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Leading Role.
The film was the subject of controversy in 2023 when Oher alleged the Tuohys tricked him into signing a conservatorship agreement
instead of legally adopting him, which prevented him from receiving royalties while the family indirectly made millions.
The film explores themes of sports, american football,
adoption, private school, education.
The tone is emotional.